<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../transforms/pp2html.xsl"?>
<PP xmlns="http://common-criteria.rhcloud.com/ns/cc" name="WIDS/WIPS EP"
    xmlns:h="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <!-- <inline-comment color='green'> Hello World QQQQ </inline-comment> -->
  <!-- <inline-comment color='blue' linebreak='yes'> Hello World QQQQ </inline-comment> -->
  <PPReference title="PP Reference">
    <ReferenceTable>
      <PPTitle>collaborative Protection Profile for Network Devices Extended Package (EP) for
				Wireless Intrusion Detection/Prevention Systems (WIDS/WIPS)
	  </PPTitle>
      <PPVersion>0</PPVersion>
      <PPAuthor>National Information Assurance Partnership</PPAuthor>
      <PPPubDate></PPPubDate>
      <PPCertificationID>unassigned</PPCertificationID>
      <CCVersion>3.1R4</CCVersion>
      <Keywords>WIDS/WIPS, Wireless Intrusion Detection/Prevention System</Keywords>
      <entry>
        <name>Registration</name>
        <description>National Information Assurance Partnership</description>
      </entry>
    </ReferenceTable>
  </PPReference>

<RevisionHistory role="draft">
    <entry>
      <version>Round 1</version>
      <date></date>
      <subject></subject>
    </entry>
  </RevisionHistory>

  <!-- <RevisionHistory role="final">
    <entry>
      <version>4.0</version>
      <date>2015-08-14</date>
      <subject>Release - significant revision</subject>
    </entry>
  </RevisionHistory>
  -->
 
 <chapter title="Introduction" id="int">
    <section title="Overview" id="ppoverview">
      This Extended Package (EP) describes security requirements for a Wireless Intrusion/Prevention System (WIDS/WIPS)
      (defined to be a IEEE 802.11 network intrusion prevention product located at the edge of a private network that 
      can collect, inspect, analyze, and react to network traffic in real-time) and is intended to provide a minimal 
      baseline set of requirements that are targeted at mitigating well defined and described threats. This EP is not 
      complete in itself, but rather extends either the collaborative Protection Profile for Network Devices (NDcPP). 
      This introduction will describe the features of a compliant Target of Evaluation (TOE), and will also discuss 
      how this EP is to be used in conjunction with the NDcPP. 
    </section>
    <section title="Terms" id="glossary"> The following sections provide both Common Criteria and
      technology terms used in this Protection Profile. <subsection title="Common Criteria Terms"
        id="ccterms">
        <glossary>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Common Criteria">CC</abbr></term>
            <description>Common Criteria for Information Technology Security
              Evaluation.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Common Evaluation Methodology">CEM</abbr></term>
            <description>Common Evaluation Methodology for Information Technology Security
              Evaluation.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Protection Profile">PP</abbr></term>
            <description>An implementation-independent set of security requirements for a category
              of products.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Security Target">ST</abbr></term>
            <description>A set of implementation-dependent security requirements for a specific
              product.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</abbr></term>
            <description> The product under evaluation. In this case, the Wireless Intrusion
                Detection/Prevention System in section <xref linkend="TOEboundary"/> and its
              supporting documentation.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="TOE Security Functionality">TSF</abbr></term>
            <description>The security functionality of the product under evaluation.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="TOE Summary Specification">TSS</abbr></term>
            <description>A description of how a <abbr linkend="TOE"/> satisfies the SFRs in a <abbr
                linkend="ST"/>. </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Security Functional Requirement">SFR</abbr></term>
            <description>A requirement for security enforcement by the <abbr linkend="TOE"/>.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Security Assurance Requirement">SAR</abbr></term>
            <description>A requirement to assure the security of the <abbr linkend="TOE"/>.</description>
          </entry>
        </glossary>
      </subsection>
      <subsection title="Technology Terms" id="techterms">
        <glossary>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Wireless Intrustion Detection/Prevention System">WIDS/WIPS</abbr></term>
            <description>Describe. This is the <abbr linkend="TOE"/>.</description>
          </entry> 
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Another Term">AT</abbr></term>
            <description>Describe the term.</description>
          </entry> 
        </glossary>
      </subsection>
	  </section>
   
   <section title="Conformance Claims" id="ConformanceClaims">
         The collaborative Protection Profile for Network Devices (NDcPP) defines the baseline Security 
         Functional Requirements (SFRs) and Security Assurance Requirements (SARs) for network infrastructure
         devices in general. This EP serves to extend the baseline set by either the NDcPP, with additional 
         SFRs and associated ‘Assurance Activities’ specific to <abbr linkend="WIDS/WIPS"/> devices. Assurance Activities are 
         the actions that the evaluator performs in order to determine a TOE’s compliance to the SFRs.
         <h:br/><h:br/>
         This EP is conformant to Parts 2 (extended) and 3 (extended) of Common Criteria
         Version 3.1, Revision 4 <cite linkend="bibCC"/>.
   </section>
   
   <section title="How to Use This Extended Package" id="Usage">
     <h:p>As an EP of the NDcPP it is expected that the content of both this EP and the base PP be appropriately 
       combined in the context of each product-specific Security Target. This EP has been specifically defined 
       such that there should be no difficulty or ambiguity in so doing. An ST must identify the applicable 
       version of the NDcPP (see http://www.niap-ccevs.org/pp/ for the current version) and this EP in its 
       conformance claims. 
     </h:p>
     
     <!--<figure entity="images/Toe.png" title="Figure 1: General TOE " id="toe"/>-->
     
   </section>
    <section title="Compliant Targets of Evaluation" id="TOEdescription">
      <h:p>This EP specifically addresses Wireless Intrusion Detection/Prevention Systems (WIDS/WIPS). A conformant 
      WIDS/WIPS is a product that provides network security administrators with the ability to monitor, collect,
      log, and react in real-time to potentially malicious network traffic.  A WIDS typically consists of multiple
      sensors that passively scan their surrounding RF environment on the WLAN radio frequency spectrum for 
      IEEE 802.11 traffic and a centralized mechanism such as a Server or Controller that processes the data 
      collected by the sensors. The WIDS/WIPS could use an Embedded (be part of the WLAN infrastructure) or 
      Overlay (independent from WLAN) architecture depending on vendor implementation.</h:p><h:br/>
      
      <h:p>This EP is focused on inspecting layers 1 and 2 of the OSI network model as the traffic that the WIDS/WIPS 
      will monitor will be wireless frames and RF spectrum for IEEE 802.11 a, b, g, and ac. Requirements for other 
      technologies (i.e., cellular) and protocols are optional.</h:p><h:br/>
      
      <h:p>Conformant TOEs will detect potentially malicious network traffic using various approaches. Broadly speaking,
      the traffic analysis could be based on identification of ‘known’ threats, or ‘unknown’ threats. Identification 
      of ‘known’ threats may be performed through pattern matching, e.g. by matching strings of characters within a frame,
      or by matching traffic patterns common with reconnaissance or denial of service (DoS) attacks. Identification of 
      ‘unknown’ threats may be performed through use of various forms of ‘anomaly’ detection whereby the WIDS/WIPS is 
      provided with (or ‘learns’/creates) a definition of ‘expected/typical’ traffic patterns, such that it’s able to 
      detect and react to ’anomalous’ (unexpected/atypical) traffic patterns. </h:p><h:br/>
      
      <h:p>The following are to be part of the evaluation:
      <h:ul>
        <h:li>Monitoring, detection and reporting capabilities offered by the WIDS/WIPS.</h:li>
        <h:li>Use of secure communication paths between WIDS/WIPS components</h:li>
        <h:li>Use of secure communication paths for WIDS/WIPS management and event monitoring.</h:li>
        <h:li>Use of secure communication paths with external components (e.g., database and log server)</h:li>
      </h:ul>
      </h:p>
    
      <figure entity="images/Toe.png" title="Figure 1: General TOE " id="toe"/>
    </section>
   
   <!--<section title="Use Cases" id="usecases">Requirements in this Protection Profile are designed to
      address the security problems in at least the following use cases. These use cases are intentionally
      very broad, as many specific use cases exist for an operating system. These use cases may also
      overlap with one another.  An operating system's functionality may even be effectively extended by
      privileged applications installed onto it.  However, these are out of scope of this PP. <usecases>
        <usecase title="End User Devices" id="enduserdevices">
          <description>
          </description>
        </usecase>
      </usecases>
    </section>
   -->
  </chapter>  
  
  <chapter title="Security Problem Definition" id="spd">
    <h:p>TWIDS/WIPS address a range of security threats related to detection of and reaction to potentially malicious WLAN 
    traffic. The malicious traffic may pose a threat to one or more endpoints on the monitored networks, or to the 
    network infrastructure, or to the TOE itself. Attacks against a WLAN could compromise the confidentiality and 
    integrity of WLAN user and system data as well as the availability of the WLAN to legitimate users. </h:p><h:br/>
    
    <h:p>The term “monitored network” is used here to represent any WLAN that the TOE is configured to monitor and detect 
    intrusions on.  The terms “WiFi Network” and “WLAN” will be used interchangeably to represent an IEEE 802.11 network.</h:p><h:br/> 
    
    <h:p>The proper installation, configuration, and administration of the WIDS/WIPS are critical to its correct operation. 
    A site is responsible for developing its security policy and configuring a rule set that the WIDS/WIPS will enforce 
    and provide an appropriate response to meet their needs, relative to their own risk analysis and their perceived threats.</h:p><h:br/>
    
    <h:p>Note that this EP does not repeat the threats identified in the NDcPP, though they all apply given the conformance 
    and hence dependence of this EP on the NDcPP. Note also that while the NDcPP contains only threats to the ability of
    the TOE to provide its security functions, this EP addresses only threats to resources in the operational environment. 
    Together the threats of the NDcPP and those defined in this EP define the comprehensive set of security threats 
    addressed by a WIDS/WIPS TOE.</h:p>
    
    
    <section title="Threats" id="threats">
      <threats>
        <threat id="T.UNAUTHORIZED_DISCLOSURE_OF_INFORMATION">
          <description> Sensitive information on a protected WLAN might be disclosed resulting from disclosure/transmitted 
            information in violation of policy, such as sending unencrypted sensitive data. The WIDS/WIPS will be capable 
            of collecting and analyzing WLAN data to detect unauthorized disclosure of information.
          </description>
          <objective-refer ref="O.QQQQ">
            <rationale>The threat T.Unauthorized_Disclosure_of_Information is countered by O.QQQQ as this
              provides for .</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </threat>
        <threat id="T.UNAUTHORIZED_ACCESS">
          <description> An attacker may attempt to gain inappropriate access to one or more networks, endpoints, or services, 
            such as by getting an end user device to connect to an unauthorized AP by impersonating an authorized AP. If 
            malicious external devices are able to communicate with devices on the protected WLAN, then those devices may be
            susceptible to the unauthorized disclosure of information.
          </description>
          <objective-refer ref="O.QQQQ">
            <rationale>The threat T.Unauthorized_Access is countered by O.QQQQ as this
              provides for .</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </threat>
        <threat id="T.DISRUPTION">
          <description> Attacks against the WLAN infrastructure might lead to denial of services (DoS) within a protected WLAN. A 
            wireless DoS may occur in two ways: at the physical layer through RF Jamming, or at the data link layer through 
            packet injection. 
          </description>
          <objective-refer ref="O.QQQQ">
            <rationale>The threat T.Disruption is countered by O.QQQQ as this
              provides for .</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </threat>
      </threats>
    </section>
    
    <section title="Assumptions" id="assumptions">
      <assumptions>
        <assumption id="A.CONNECTIONS">
          <description> It is assumed that the TOE is connected to distinct networks in a manner that ensures that the TOE 
            security policies will be enforced on all applicable network traffic flowing among the attached networks. </description>
          <objective-refer ref="OE.CONNECTIONS">
            <rationale> The operational environment objective OE.CONNECTIONS is realized through A.CONNECTIONS.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </assumption>
      </assumptions>
    </section>
  </chapter>
  
  <chapter title="Security Objectives" id="obj">
    <section title="Security Objectives for the TOE" id="SecurityObjectivesTOE">
      <SOs>
        <SO id="O.SYSTEM_MONITORING">
          <description> 
            To be able to analyze and react to potential network policy violations, the IPS must be able to 
            collect and store essential data elements of network traffic on monitored networks. <h:br/>
            (O.SYSTEM_MONITORING->)
          </description>
          <!--<component-refer ref="fau_gen.1"/>-->
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.ANALYSIS_OF_NETWORK_TRAFFIC_POLICY_VIOLATIONS">
          <description> 
            Entities that reside on or communicate across monitored networks must have network activity effectively
            analyzed for potential violations of approved network usage.<h:br/>
            
            The TOE must be able to effectively analyze data collected from monitored networks to reduce the risk of
            unauthorized disclosure of information, inappropriate access to services, and misuse of network resources.<h:br/>
            
            (O.IPS_ANALYZE->)
          </description>
          <!--<component-refer ref=""/>-->
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.REACTION_TO_NETWORK_TRAFFIC_POLICY_VIOLATIONS">
          <description> The TOE must be able to react as configured by the administrators to isolate/contain 
            WLAN devices that have been determined to violate administrator-defined IPS policies.  <h:br/>
            (O.IPS_REACT->)
          </description>
          <!--<component-refer ref=""/>-->
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.TOE_ADMINISTRATION">
          <description> To address the threat of unauthorized administrator access that is defined in the base PP, 
            Conformant TOEs will provide the functions necessary for an administrator to configure the IDS/IPS Capabilities of the TOE.
            <h:br/>
            (O.TOE_ADMINISTRATION->)
          </description>
          <!--<component-refer ref=""/>-->
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.INSECURE_OPERATIONS">
          <description> There may be instances where the TOE’s hardware malfunctions or the integrity of the TOE’s software is compromised, 
            the latter being due to malicious or non-malicious intent. To address the concern of the TOE operating outside of its hardware 
            or software specification, the TOE will shut down upon discovery of a problem reported via the self-test mechanism.
            <h:br/>
            (O.FAIL_SECURE ->)
          </description>
          <!--<component-refer ref=""/>-->
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.TRUSTED_COMMUNICATIONS">
          <description> To further address the threat of untrusted communications channels that is defined in the base PP, conformant TOEs 
            will provide trusted communications between distributed components if any exist. <h:br/>
            (O.TRUSTED_COMMUNICATIONS->)
          </description>
          <!--<component-refer ref=""/>-->
        </SO>
      </SOs>
    </section>
    <section title="Security Objectives for the Operational Environment"
      id="SecurityObjectivesTOEorEnvironment">The following security objectives for the operational
      environment assist the TOE in correctly providing its security functionality.
      These track with the assumptions about the environment. 
      <SOEs>
        <SOE id="OE.PLATFORM">
          <description>The <abbr linkend="WIDS/WIPS"/> relies on being installed on trusted
            hardware.</description>
        </SOE>
        <SOE id="OE.CONNECTIONS">
          <description> TOE administrators will ensure that the TOE is installed in a manner that will allow the TOE to effectively 
            enforce its policies on network traffic of monitored networks. </description>
        </SOE>
        <SOE id="OE.PROPER_ADMIN">
          <description> The administrator of the is not careless, willfully
            negligent or hostile, and administers the OS within compliance of the applied enterprise
            security policy. </description>
        </SOE>
      </SOEs></section>
    <section title="Security Objectives Rationale" id="SOR">This section describes how the
      assumptions, threats, and organizational security policies map to the security objectives.
      <InsertSPDCorrespondence/></section>
  </chapter>
  
  <chapter title="Security Requirements" id="req">This chapter describes the security requirements
    which have to be fulfilled by the <abbr linkend="WIDS/WIPS"/>. Those requirements comprise functional
    components from Part 2 and assurance components from Part 3 of <cite linkend="bibCC"/>. The
    following notations are used: <h:ul>
      <h:li>
        <h:b>Refinement</h:b> operation (denoted by <h:b>bold text</h:b>): is used to add details to a
        requirement, and thus further restricts a requirement.</h:li>
      <h:li>
        <h:b>Selection</h:b> (denoted by <h:i>italicized text</h:i>): is used to select one or more options
        provided by the [CC] in stating a requirement.</h:li>
      <h:li>
        <h:b>Assignment</h:b> operation (denoted by <h:span class="assignable-content">italicized text</h:span>): is used to assign a
        specific value to an unspecified parameter, such as the length of a password. Showing the
        value in square brackets indicates assignment.</h:li>
      <h:li>
        <h:b>Iteration</h:b> operation: are identified with a number inside parentheses (e.g.
        "(1)")</h:li>
    </h:ul>
    <section title="Security Functional Requirements" id="SFRs">The Security Functional Requirements
      included in this section are derived from Part 2 of the Common Criteria for Information
      Technology Security Evaluation, Version 3.1, Revision 4, with additional extended functional
      components. 
      <subsection title="QQQQ" id="QQQQ">
        <f-component id="QQQ_QQQ.1" name="QQQQQ" status="threshold">
          <f-element id="QQQ_QQQ.1.1">
            <title> A threshold requirement.
            </title>
            <note role="application"></note>
            <aactivity>	
              <tss>The evaluator shall verify that the <abbr linkend="TSS"/>... 
              </tss>
              <guidance>The evaluator shall also review the Operational Guidance to ensure that it
                contains instructions on configuring ...
              </guidance>
              <tests> The evaluator shall perform the following tests:<h:br/>
                <testlist>
                  <test>Test 1</test>
                  <test>Test 2</test>
                </testlist>
              </tests>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        
        <f-component id="QQQ_QQQ.2" name="QQQQO" status="objective">
          <f-element id="QQQ_QQQ.1.2">
            <title> An objective requirement.
            </title>
            <note role="application"></note>
            <aactivity>	    
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        
        <f-component id="QQQ_QQQ.3" name="QQQQOP" status="optional">
          <f-element id="QQQ_QQQ.1.3">
            <title> An optional requirement.
            </title>
            <note role="application"></note>
            <aactivity>	    
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        
        <f-component id="QQQ_QQQ.4" name="QQQQOS" status="sel-based">
          <f-element id="QQQ_QQQ.1.4">
            <title> A selection based requirement.  The TSF shall: 
              <selectables>
                <selectable>selection 1</selectable>
                <selectable>selection 2</selectable>
                <selectable>selection 3</selectable>
              </selectables> and no others. 
            </title>
            <note role="application"></note>
            <aactivity>	    
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection title="Cryptographic Support (FCS)" id="fcs">
        <f-component id="fcs_ckm_ext.3" name="Protection of Key and Key Material" status="sel-based">
          <!--<selection-depends req="ftp_itc_ext.1.1"/>-->
          <f-element id="fcs_ckm_ext.3.1">
            <title>This is an embedded selection requirement. The TSF shall <selectables>
              <selectable>not store keys in non-volatile memory</selectable>
                <selectable>only store keys in non-volatile memory when wrapped as specified in
                  <!--<linkref linkend="FCS_COP_EXT.2"/> --> unless the key meets any one of following
                  criteria: <selectables linebreak="yes">
                    <selectable>The plaintext key is not part of the key chain as specified in  </selectable>
                    <selectable>The plaintext key is a key split that is combined as specified in and the other half of the key split is
                      either 
                      <selectables>
                        <selectable>wrapped as specified in </selectable>
                        <selectable>derived and not stored in non-volatile memory </selectable>
                      </selectables>
                    </selectable>
                    <selectable>The plaintext key is stored on an external storage device for use as
                      an authorization factor </selectable>
                    <selectable>The plaintext key is the public portion of the key pair</selectable>
                  </selectables>
                </selectable>
              </selectables>. 
            </title>
            <note role="application">The plaintext key storage in non-volatile memory is allowed for
              several reasons. 
            </note>
            <aactivity>
              <tss>The evaluator shall verify the <abbr linkend="TSS"/> for a high level
              description of method used to protect keys stored in non-volatile memory.<h:br/> The
              evaluator shall verify the <abbr linkend="TSS"/> to ensure ...
              </tss>
              <guidance>N/A</guidance>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
      </subsection>   
     </section>
  </chapter>
 
  <chapter title="Security Assurance Requirements" id="SARs">
    <h:p>This EP does not define any SARs beyond those defined within the NDcPP. It is important 
      to note that a TOE that is evaluated against this EP is inherently evaluated against NDcPP. 
      When evaluating the TOE, it is necessary to apply the SARs defined for the base PP to the 
      entire TOE and not just the portion that is described by the base PP.</h:p>   
  </chapter>
  <!-- 
  <appendix title="Inherently Satisfied Requirements" id="satisfiedreqs"> This
    appendix lists requirements that should be considered satisfied by products
    successfully evaluated against this Protection Profile.  
    However, these requirements are not featured explicitly as SFRs and should not be
    included in the <abbr linkend="ST"/>.  
    They are not included as standalone SFRs because it would
    increase the time, cost, and complexity of evaluation.  This approach is permitted
    by <cite linkend="bibCC"/> Part 1, <h:b>8.2 Dependencies between components</h:b>.
    <h:br/>
    This information benefits systems engineering activities which call for inclusion of 
    particular security controls.  Evaluation against the Protection Profile
    provides evidence that these controls are present and have been evaluated.
    
    
    
    <table>
      <tr class="header">
        <td>Requirement</td>
        <td>Rationale for Satisfaction</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>FIA_UAU.1 - Timing of authentication</td>
        <td>
          <linkref linkend="FIA_AFL.1"/> FIA_AFL.1 implicitly requires that the OS perform all necessary actions, 
          including those on behalf of the user who has not been authenticated, 
          in order to authenticate;
          therefore it is duplicative to include these actions as a 
          separate assignment and test.
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>FAU_GEN.2 - User identity association</td>
        <td>
          <linkref linkend="FAU_GEN.1.2"/>explicitly requires that the OS record
          any user account associated with each event; therefore, it is duplicative
          to include a separate requirement to associate a user account with each
          event.
        </td>
      </tr>
    </table>
    
  </appendix>
  -->
  
  <appendix title="Optional Requirements" id="optional"> 
    As indicated in <secref linkend="ccl"/>,
    the baseline requirements (those that must be performed by the <abbr linkend="WIDS/WIPS"/>) are
    contained in the body of this PP. Additionally, there are three other types of requirements
    specified in <appref linkend="optional"/>, <appref linkend="sel-based"/>, and <appref
      linkend="objective"/>. The first type (in this Appendix) are requirements that can be included
    in the <abbr linkend="ST"/>, but are not required in order for a OS to claim conformance to
    this PP. The second type (in <appref linkend="sel-based"/>) are requirements based on selections
    in the body of the PP: if certain selections are made, then additional requirements in that
    appendix must be included. The third type (in <appref linkend="objective"/> are components that
    are not required in order to conform to this PP, but will be included in the baseline
    requirements in future versions of this PP, so adoption by vendors is encouraged. Note that the
    ST author is responsible for ensuring that requirements that may be associated with those in
    <appref linkend="optional"/>, <appref linkend="sel-based"/>, and <appref linkend="objective"/>
    but are not listed (e.g., FMT-type requirements) are also included in the ST. 
  </appendix>

  <appendix title="Selection-Based Requirements" id="sel-based"> As indicated in the introduction to
    this PP, the baseline requirements (those that must be performed by the OS or its underlying
    platform) are contained in the body of this PP. There are additional requirements based on
    selections in the body of the PP: if certain selections are made, then additional requirements
    below will need to be included. 
  </appendix>

  <appendix title="Objective Requirements" id="objective"> This appendix includes requirements that
    specify security functionality which also addresses threats. The requirements are not currently
    mandated in the body of this PP as they describe security functionality not yet widely-available
    in commercial technology. However, these requirements may be included in the ST such that the
    OS is still conformant to this PP, and it is expected that they be included as soon as
    possible. 
  </appendix>

  <appendix title="References" id="biblio">
    <bibliography>
      <entry id="bibCC">
        <tag>CC</tag>
        <description>Common Criteria for Information Technology Security Evaluation - <h:ul>
            <h:li><h:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART1V3.1R4.pdf">Part
                1: Introduction and General Model</h:a>, CCMB-2012-09-001, Version 3.1 Revision 4,
              September 2012.</h:li>
            <h:li><h:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART2V3.1R4.pdf">Part
                2: Security Functional Components</h:a>, CCMB-2012-09-002, Version 3.1 Revision 4,
              September 2012.</h:li>
            <h:li><h:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART3V3.1R4.pdf">Part
                3: Security Assurance Components</h:a>, CCMB-2012-09-003, Version 3.1 Revision 4,
              September 2012.</h:li>
          </h:ul></description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bibCEM">
        <tag>CEM</tag>
        <description>
          <h:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CEMV3.1R4.pdf">Common
            Evaluation Methodology for Information Technology Security - Evaluation Methodology</h:a>,
          CCMB-2012-09-004, Version 3.1, Revision 4, September 2012. </description>
      </entry>
  </bibliography>
  </appendix>

  <appendix title="Acronyms" id="acronyms">
    <acronyms>
      <entry>
        <term>AES</term>
        <description>Advanced Encryption Standard</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>DES</term>
        <description>Data Encryption Standard</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>DNS</term>
        <description>Domain Name System</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>EAP</term>
        <description>Extensible Authentication Protocol</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>EP</term>
        <description>Extended Package</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>FIPS</term>
        <description>Federal Information Processing Standards</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>HTTP</term>
        <description>Hypertext Transfer Protocol</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>HTTPS</term>
        <description>Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>IP</term>
        <description>Internet Protocol</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>ISO</term>
        <description>International Organization for Standardization</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>NIAP</term>
        <description>National Information Assurance Partnership</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>NIST</term>
        <description>National Institute of Standards and Technology</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>OCSP</term>
        <description>Online Certificate Status Protocol</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>OID</term>
        <description>Object Identifier</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>OMB</term>
        <description>Office of Management and Budget</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>OS</term>
        <description>Operating System</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>PII</term>
        <description>Personally Identifiable Information</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>PKI</term>
        <description>Public Key Infrastructure</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>PP</term>
        <description>Protection Profile</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>RFC</term>
        <description>Request for Comment</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>SHA</term>
        <description>Secure Hash Algorithm</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>TLS</term>
        <description>Transport Layer Security</description>
      </entry>
    </acronyms>
  </appendix>
  
</PP>
